hello everyone and welcome to this video
on deploying kestra on
AWS let's Jump Right In uh so here I am
on AWS Council home if you're not
familiar with AWS or don't have an
account uh you could just Google make a
free
account
ews sign
up and sign up for a free account uh and
I'm not really sure how it's decided but
typically when I make a new AWS account
I get an email within a day or two
asking if I want uh $300 in free credits
uh and once you sign up for the first
time there's a lot of free tier Services
you can use experiment with uh some of
those we will be using in this video but
even if you've had an account for a
while and it's going to charge you just
running through this walkth through and
then bringing down the resource is after
will'll probably charge you less than $2
or3 at
most okay and we are going to be
following the kastra documentation more
or less if we just Google kastra
AWS deployment that's
eks let's see here click the first
link and I'm going to go to the docs and
over here see if I can make this a
little
bigger the installation guide that we
will be following is going to
be AWS ec2 with Amazon RDS and
S3 okay so just at a glance if we look
here we're going to create an ec2
instance and install
Docker uh generate keys if you're more
of a learn by reading type of person you
can follow the documentations I use this
video as a reference and vice versa I'm
going to go ahead and start an ec2
instance looking here with Ubuntu four
gigs of memory and two virtual
CPUs so if we just click on
ec2 or we could have searched up
here go to
instances and we can just launch
instance and I will call this kestra for
the name of our
instance and we're going to want
Ubuntu looks like this is the latest at
the
moment and if we scroll down as the
documentation said we are going to want
4 gigs of memory two virtual CPUs so
that is the
t2
medium okay and if you have a SSH key
you could just look for key pairs in the
search up here upload your public key
and select that here if you don't that's
okay we're just going to create new key
pair RSA is
fine and I'm just going to call this
castra
key and we'll see that downloaded
there and scrolling down we're going to
create a security group for this
instance allow SSH traffic from
anywhere if you want to be super secure
you could put your IP address but
chances are your IP address is
determined by your internet service
provider and they can change that at any
time so just to be safe not really
locking this down I'm just going to say
from anywhere and we will be accessing
this over
https and just check that box
looking here 8 gigs of storage is more
than enough so that looks good and
launch
instance that will take a few minutes
while that's running I'm just going to
open up a terminal
here and as we saw our kri key.pem is in
our
downloads I'm going to change to my SSH
directory and I'm just going to uh move
the little squiggly means my home
directory let me make this much bigger
there we go I'm going to go for my home
directory
downloads castra key.pem where do I want
to move that to my current
directory okay and now if we LS we see
that is there and one other thing or
maybe two or three other things that
make our life much easier we're going to
make a config file just so we can get to
this instance in Visual Studio code if
you're just using SSH you'll need to use
Vim or Nano as a text editor to change
the docker composed CRA file and it's
just easier in Visual Studio code in my
opinion so we need to Nano config to if
I can spell here config to make our
configuration file
and I just have
this in a text
document so host with a capital H uh you
can name it whatever you want just
something friendly where it's easy to
remember uh the host name is going to be
the IP
address and we will get that from our
instance in a moment and the user is
going to be Ubuntu
and where is this key
again this TIY I think it's called is my
home directory.
SSH kestra key.
head and let me check if we have an IP
for our instance yet still initializing
but we do have an
IP let's see if I can contrl C to copy
that and back
here contrl shift vrl X to exit y to
save the modified buffer and just enter
to keep the name the same and we can try
that out with SSH ec2 permission denied
public key okay let's do an ls- la8
let's see if we modify our P to 700 I
believe it
is let's up here twice actually let me
contr L to move that to the
top and we'll try that
again okay so that was the issue a
little gotcha there just
remember I feel like it happens
sometimes and not others but just 700
permission on your key and you should be
good all right we can exit
there now we go back to the
documentation
and scroll down we've set up our ec2
instance and we can
SSH and then we want to install Docker
and Docker compose and they have the
instructions
here and if you scroll down it tells you
all the commands you need to
run I honestly just like to put those
into a file make it executable and and
then run it it's just much easier so
actually I'll just do that
here we'll go back to our
instance and
here me line that up a little nicer to
look at
maybe and we're going
to make a
file a little delay there and I'll just
call this in
stall
Docker like
that and again I have the instructions
just
copied
here the one command that that isn't in
the docker documentation is believe it's
called the shebang the pound exclamation
point telling this what program to run
these commands with uh in my case I want
to use Bash so that's
there and if we look just update get the
certificates all that good stuff and if
we switch back to the docker
documentation you can see that's just
all these
commands and there should be a post
install yes there and
then it used to be you had to add the
docker group I don't believe you need to
anymore I think the install takes care
of that so I don't have that in mind but
then add the user to the docker group
and new grp Docker is the same as just
logging out logging back in so there
permissions apply to your user you're in
the docker group and you can run
Docker okay all that out of the way back
here in Nano controll X Y to save the
modified buffer enter to keep the name
and then we just need to make it
executable with
chod plus X install Docker you can tab
to
autocomplete and slash install
Docker and that does take a few
minutes to download all those packages
and install them so we'll pick back up
after that is done
installing okay that was actually really
quick only took a minute or two and we
can test to to make sure we have Docker
and it's working correctly by just
typing let me make this a little cleaner
Docker
run hello dash
world and it's pulling it it ran it
hello from Docker we now have our ec2
instance with Docker and Docker compose
installed we can go ahead and exit the
terminal and we'll switch to Visual
Studio code which is just a little bit
easier to work with in my
opinion so I already have that installed
on my system so I'll just open that here
if you don't have the SSH extension
installed you just need to click over
here extensions SSH It's usually the top
one remote SSH from Microsoft install
that and then down here see if I can
make this a little bit bigger we can
click open remote window connect in the
current window and it reads our config
file and looks for the
different Keys we have or the hosts that
we have listed I should say I only have
one
ec2 so I'll
click let that set
up okay and then open folder there's
nothing on the CC to instance so just go
into the home
directory trust the author trust the
authors of all files in the parent
folder home uh yes that's
fine close that I'm going to make a
directory just
to make it a little cleaner so I'm going
to hit control the dick Mark the key
usually underneath your Escape key and
then I have a terminal here and you can
see we are on our virtu ual
machine
okay now the next step let's look at the
documentation download and run
kestra so we just need to copy that
command and hit
enter and now we have actually LS
to list the files oh I did not CD into
the Castro directory but that's okay I'm
just going to move the doer compose from
the current
directory to
kestra oh I don't think I made that
directory make directory kestra
all right there we
are and now we can go ahead and open
that in the
window and we can see the docker compose
file here if you're familiar with Docker
you can read through this get a feel of
what's going on if you're not you can
just wave your hand at this and remove
the parts that I do and that's fine as
well so we have some volumes so places
to store data we've got postgress for
the metadata castra data for storage you
can see this is just pulling the images
doing some health checks
configuring the connection to the
database and then forwarding the ports
from the docker Network to the local
machine okay so let's switch back to the
do mentation
here
and set the basic authentication to True
which means rather than when we pull up
kestra and just going right into the
guey we will be prompted for a username
and password in order to access it and
we do need a valid email
address scroll down a little bit or
actually up and we we are looking for
the basic
off I hope that's big enough I'm going
to make it a little
bigger and trying to keep it still
usable for me basic off is
true and I'm just going to use an email
address I happen to have a noob forever
data
course at
gmail.com for the
password I'm just going to put KRA W if
you're going to keep this up and running
for a while I would suggest a much
stronger
password but for this walk through I'm
going to be taking down everything after
this so that's
fine
okay back to the
documentation it says to start castra
but I'm going to skip that step and wait
till the end just because I'm pretty
positive everything is going to work
going down to allow external
traffic so it
exposes 8080 as the port so what we need
to
do is let's see here we are going to
need
to allow that to come
in so we will need to look at the
security groups let me switch back
there and look for security
groups
ec2 if it lets me click on let me just
go to oh there we go okay so we have our
default Security Group and then the
launch wizard was created when we
launched our ec2 instance if you had a
bunch of ec2 instances already running
or have spun them up in the past you
might have a bunch of launch wizard
security groups here just go to the
latest one click into that you're going
to want to edit the inbound rules keep
those we're going to add a custom
TCP and that's going to be on
8080 and again just in case our I IP
changes we're going to allow it traffic
from anywhere and we'll just save that
rule okay good to go
there switching back
we scroll down use awsrds post rust as a
database
backend let's see so we will go to the
console I'm just going to click that to
open it nice and
easy create a database choose post
address says you can also use my SQL I'm
going to stick with postgress as it's
recommended a set a username and
password and we are going to connect it
to our ec2 compute resource
Source okay I might need to glance back
at this but let's get that going so I'm
going to do DB
instances create a
database and let's see standard
create not sure the difference between
those
two I'm just going to call this
kestra D
I'm going to use the free tier it's not
going to be I'm the only one that's
going to be using it so doesn't really
need too much
power let's see self-manage to create
our own password and I'll leave the
username as
postgress and I'm going to make this
super secure and use kestra PW
again actually let me count out uh k s r
a p w okay it is eight characters if you
noticed it needs to be at least eight
characters so if you just tried putting
in PW got down to the end and it said
you can't create it make the password
eight
characters all right we can connect to
our ec2 compute resource there we
go all right I'm going to choose an
existing DB subnet
so that's fine
VPC not sure if we need to select that
or not let's scroll down
here okay we
did the existing and we did the launch
wizard
beautiful so that all looks good
don't need performance insights I don't
believe that costs
anything and that all looks good we'll
go ahead and create the
database and let that spin
up so while that's going we'll switch
back
here and we do not need our postgress
data volume
here going down we don't need the postr
service at all
and I think that takes care of
everything except maybe oh depends on
postgress so that looks
good and
actually I think I may have
yes forgot to get the health check so
let's go
ahead and we'll get rid of
those okay and we'll update that in a
moment the data sources postest but
again get rid of the dependon I'm just
going to contrl S you see this white dot
up here that means it's not saved I've
had Visual Studio crash on me a number
of times and lost quite a bit of work so
crl
s you see that X up there means your
work is
saved
okay close
that so still creating the instance
while that's going we can move
on or actually we'll Circle back to the
create kestra database cuz I feel like
the database takes a few minutes to come
up it's not too bad but it would be a
wait we can update the username and
password and
actually let me switch back
here so the username we had was
postgress and we use the password castra
PW
and we're just going to need to replace
this part with our connection string
which we'll get from the database in
just a
moment and we'll see how that's
doing so creating while that's going we
can go ahead and set up the S3 and then
we can bring it all up at once
okay so to set up the S3 storage we want
to go to the S3 console create a
bucket and create a new user with AWS S3
full
access okay so up here I'm just going to
search for
S3 click on
that we'll go to S3
here and if you have buckets already uh
you might get a different screen
at the moment I don't have any uh in
this a AWS account uh so I'll just click
create bucket general purpose in the
same
region and I'll just call this kestra
data I'll be aware that this name cannot
be reused as long as I'm using it it
does need to be globally unique uh so
whatever name you choose if someone in
Japan or Kazakhstan or France France or
South Africa has already used that name
for one of their S3 buckets it will not
let you use
it
okay and everything else is default we
don't need versioning
tags and we'll create the bucket while
that's going we will go to I am and
create our user with permissions to
write data to this
bucket and
once we're on the IM
screen we'll go to users and we'll
create
a user
and I'll just call this
kestra storage
user and go
next add user to groups I'm going to
create a
group and I'm just going to call this
bucket
users and down here if we search for
S3 we want Amazon S3 full
access which means they have full access
well
to S3 buckets uh they can create them
delete them the objects inside as
well in production you would want to
limit these permissions to probably just
reading and writing because you don't
need to create or destroy the bucket
itself but that's good enough for our
purposes so that looks
good check the box to add the user to
the
group and create
user all right let's see how our
database is doing all right it's
available if we click on
that the end point is what we want
here and I'm just going to copy
that and if we look back at the
documentation that will walk you through
let's see for new users we will need to
create an access
key I guess we should finish that part
up first let me go ahead and paste this
in here real
quick and again contrl s to
save and if we click on our user create
access key we want an application
running on an AWS compute
service giving us a little warning
there don't need to do the tag and we
are just going to copy the access
key actually there is one thing we need
to add and a few things we need to
remove
first so
here if we control home we don't need
the storage volume
anymore so no volumes at
all we can remove this from the
volumes and scrolling down to where
that's
defined rather than local what we want
is
S3 so we can just click here copy the
whole
thing let's switch
back and if you highlight and shift and
do the uh square bracket the one to the
right if you're looking at your keyboard
that will indent the block or sorry
control square bracket to the right that
will move your
indentation and you just need to line
that up we are already under kestra so
let me take that
out and we just need to line that up
with the other pieces here the server
the
que all right
okay so now we just need our access key
secret key region and
bucket if we switch back
here let me show that's the access key I
can just click
copy and if we switch
back let me Center that a little bit we
will keep the quotes there just be aware
and we'll paste that in for the secret
key
copy that as
well and
region let's see
here oops let me go back to S3 to get
that because that was our user that can
access the bucket and not the bucket
itself
and it's actually just this last part
here in my case Us East one so I'll copy
that and I have a very bad memory so
let's see I think I called that
kestra storage better double
check KRA data darn okay cter data
contrl s make sure I save that
and let me zoom out a little bit
here hopefully that's still big enough
but we have postgress
gone and we have our connection
string username and
password all looks
good so Moment of Truth uh control tick
mark again that little tick under your
Escape key if you're doing this all in
terminal uh you can just go ahead and
type the command Docker compose up if
you don't want to see the output you can
do- D I usually don't do that especially
the first time because if there were any
errors they will be printed to the
terminal and I want to see
those oh and make sure you're in the
directory where your Docker composed
file is in my case
kestra and we'll let that
pole okay I did get an errror it can be
a little bit cryptic here but I've
actually done this mistake before so if
we look carefully here uh we should be
able to see database kestra does not
exist I skipped that step I think I said
we were going to circle back to it and I
just did not and that's probably easiest
easiest way to do it is in the terminal
SSH the shorthand name from our config
file all right so we just need to uh
download the postgress client I believe
it is and create that
database so that was way back
here oh that was after the create
database scrolling too fast so we just
need to install the client
yes that's
fine
and create DB now we will need the end
point there so we'll grab that
again and switch back to
RDS grab
that paste it in here
there we
go
and the username we used was
postgress actually I'll
just I can move this piece down
dasu
postr Port which is
5432 - P
5432 and and the database we want to
connect is
kestra it's asking for our password
which we set in RDS in my case kestra
PW and the terminal got a little hinky
there but I'm pretty sure it worked we
can test it out by just trying to bring
up the docker container again and see if
we get an error should be much quicker
this time uh because the images have
already been
pulled so we'll give that a
moment looks good so far and while
that's going on uh we just need to grab
the IP address of our
instance could also look in the config
file
and I hate that they don't have a copy
option on the IP but I just contrl
C and that's going to be the port that
we allowed in which is
8080 all right and again with my bad
memory I need to remember the username
and
password so I'll just copy that and
kestra PW for the
password
beautiful make that a little
bigger and we will go ahead and switch
to dark mode I think it just looks a
little nicer has my right time zone that
all looks good we can go to
flows and we can create a flow we can
also go to the editor
I'm going to skip the tour see if I can
make that just a little bit bigger
and actually going to import a really
simple flow I exported on a different
day and I'm going to click into
it and go to the editor let's see I am
just going to copy this
here go to flow
I'm going to create a new flow paste it
in there and then call it
demo and save it and I am going to
delete the one I imported doesn't really
matter
but I don't know it's just easier in my
opinion that way okay pretty simple flow
here there's only two tasks I'm actually
going to comment out this last one here
it's just going to
to grab this Global power plant database
I guess if I zoom in it messes up that
line a little bit and it just goes ahead
and downloads it where is it going to
download it to it's going to download it
to storage which we have set to
S3 so if we switch back over here and go
to
S3 we have our
bucket and if we look in here we just
created it there's nothing in there so
let's go ahead and run our flow and see
what
happens and if we just
execute I'm going
to contrl S to save I'm really horrible
at that and now it doesn't warn us uh we
have green so if we
look it downloaded the
file in kestra these downloads and any
data you're pulling down is ephemeral
would make this video much longer if I
went into it there's other videos out
there about how to pass those files
along to other tasks how to send them to
another S3 bucket save it load it into a
database but just remember it's an
orchestrator so the data isn't meant to
stay on this storage so it will store it
in temporary directories and if we
switch back to our bucket and just do a
refresh we see that now so if we go in
we see we have our Nam space that's
going to be our
flow and that's going to be the
execution and if we go into tasks the
task of download
file and then we have our data there if
you're running kestra just in Docker by
itself it will automatically clean these
up uh if you're running it with this
configuration you do need to add an
extra step which you probably saw so let
me go ahead and go up many directories
here and I'm just going
to delete
that and it's warning me that there are
objects uh beneath this directory
level so I need to just put permanently
delete saying yes I am sure any objects
below this directory I want deleted as
well
okay so if we go back here we still have
our bucket but now it's
empty and switching
back I'm going to go to my flows again
the download file
flow open that an
editor and then there's another task in
this
flow if I can uncomment that there we go
and I just use uh control whack the key
with the question mark in the slash to
comment and
uncomment and this is just going to make
sure all those files are removed contrl
s successfully saved
and I'm going to execute that
again and it's downloading the file this
is the flow there are two tasks one
being download file the other being
clean
files and if we click in there
success and we go back to
S3 and we see the we have the whack demo
download file executions but that data
from that execution is not there that
data is still preserved in the database
so we can go back in
look we go back to our dashboard we can
see that those all
succeeded okay that's pretty much it for
this walk through but I will walk
through the cleanup which can be a
little extensive in AWS so at this point
I'm going to go ahead and switch back to
the docs and just leave it here with if
you like kestra and you like what
they're doing you can show your
appreciation by starring the
GitHub I'm not logged in at the moment
but if you are you can star the repo
it's like giving the developers a little
round of applause know that you're happy
with their work
if you have any questions or get stuck
need help you can hit this button to
join the slack a lot of knowledgeable
people ready to help if you go pretty
much anywhere on the kestra website
you'll see these two things which again
the slack is the best place to go to get
help all right so clean up here we
go switching back here I am going to I'm
going to close kestra cuz well we're in
the cleanup phase and I'm going to go to
RDS go to my
instances and
action if you are just pausing your
instance you don't want to get charged
you don't want this to keep running uh
you can say stop temporarily but no it
will automatically restart in 7 Days uh
that's just one of the quirks of it
but just be aware you can stop
temporarily
but if you're taking a few weeks off
just remember every six days log in and
say temporarily stop again in my case
I'm done with this one so I am going to
uh
Delete I don't need a final snapshot I
don't need to keep my automatic
copies and I'm going to say
delete and even though it doesn't matter
I'm going to come back here to my
terminal contrl C and stop
kestra and let's see we strongly
recommend oh delete
me not sure why that's not working
I may need to stop at first
but okay you know what I am going to go
ahead
and stop
temporarily and let that just wind down
and while that's going I'm going to go
to
ec2 and I'm going to go ahead
and terminate the
instance terminate it like
that all right that's shutting down
let's see what else S3
I'm going to delete that
bucket and it's going to have me empty
the bucket of all objects first
so there's nothing in
there and permanently delete we also did
create a user which
is very bad to leave out there dangling
in case somebody gets a hold of your
keys
and we're going to delete that
user testra storage
user all right we also created a
security
group or actually the user group I'm
sorry but yeah let's go ahead and do
that
one user groups we don't need that group
anymore bucket
users
delete and security
groups which are tricky here so stick
with me okay launch
wizard we should be able to delete this
one as long long as as long as our ec2
instance came down okay default I do
want to keep all right that seems just
like a shadow so ec2 RDS which I always
get them backwards
but okay so this allowed outbound
traffic on 5432 the other one allows
inbound traffic so uh that allows the
communication between postgress and
kestra or whatever application you're
using but just know you need to come in
here it will not let you delete it
unless you delete the rules first oh
edit the outbound rules
delete so now it doesn't have any and
now that we don't have any rules we
should be able to delete the security
group try RDS is still winding
down so let me go back to security
groups I think we did ec2 RDS now we'll
do RDS
ec2 notice no outbound rules but we do
have an inbound
Rule and we will edit the inbound
rules delete
that that's
stopped going to
delete maybe I just just didn't see that
box last time or it wasn't there because
it was
running but now that's
deleting that does take a bit of
time let's switch back and see if it
knows it's deleting so it should let us
delete those security groups
all right we'll give that another
minute I don't mind hanging out with
y'all okay few minutes it just
disappeared didn't even have to hit
refresh which is always nice now let's
try that one more time security
groups and I'm going to see if I can zap
them both at the same time here
all right just be aware I've had it
happen I believe where everything went
away and it was still giving me a
warning on this uh if you are getting
that make sure you delete the rules as
we just did go into the security groups
delete all the rules uh if you still
can't delete it uh you're probably good
to
go do whatever come back to it the next
day might take some time for to sync in
on Amazon's side and then
delete and give that a
refresh and now we are back to just
having our default Security Group again
things we were checking for cleanup
ec2 not running instances but instances
in
general not sure why I still have one oh
that's just going to take a little bit
to go away
but it is terminated
RDS no instances there
S3 pretty sure I deleted
that okay maybe I missed a check check
box that's why we double check just to
make sure let's see I am
users and
here no
users no groups one last thing if you
really wanted to SSH keys I always
forget what it's
called maybe key
manager key pairs
and if we look
here you can delete that um especially
if you have other things running in your
AWS account oh delete that's probably
case
sensitive I just like to make sure
there's a thorough
clean okay so I think that takes care of
it all all if you're were going to put
this project down for any amount of time
you could copy that doer compose file
and use it as a template if you're
recreating it of course you'll need to
update the uh the S3 access key location
name of the bucket uh the connection
connection string to your uh database
and the password uh if you set it
differently you'll need to recreate the
oestra the kestra
database inside the
RDS but just a good way to get you up
and going again if you're just going to
take a break but again that's it for
this video I would highly encourage you
to Star the kestra repo I'll let them
know you appreciate their work join the
slack if you have any questions or
comments anything like that and
hopefully you enjoyed this video